Finding aid for the Sylvia Plath collection MRBC.MS.00045
Mortimer Rare Book Collection
- Writings, 1949-1963; 1; 9.3 linear feet (17 boxes; 8 oversize folders)
  - Poetry, approximately 1950-2008; 5; 7.2 linear feet (12 boxes; 8 oversize folders)
    - Holograph of "Purdah", undated; 3 pages; Written on pink Smith College memorandum paper. (Box 12, Folder 205, Item 1)
      Holograph of "Purdah" with the definition of purdah written at the top in Sylvia Plath's hand.
    - Typescript of "Purdah", 1962 October 28; 2 pages; Typed on pink Smith College memorandum paper. (Box 12, Folder 205, Item 2)
      Revised typescript of "Purdah"
    - Typescript of "Purdah", 1962 October 28-29; 6 pages (Box 12, Folder 205, Item 3)
      Revised typescript (original and carbons) of "Purdah."
    - Photocopy of a typescript of the last seven stanzas of "Purdah", undated; 1 pages (Box 12, Folder 205, Item 4)
      Photocopy of a revised typescript of the last 7 stanzas of "Purdah" with "The Fearful": item 5, page 1, on the back of the page.
      Original: Box 9, Folder 95, item 5.
    - Typescript of the last eleven stanzas of "Purdah", undated; 4 pages (Box 12, Folder 205, Item 5)
      Original and carbon typescript of the last 11 stanzas of "Purdah" double spaced and revised.
    - Photocopy of printed version of "Purdah", 1963 August (Box 12, Folder 205, Item 6)
      Photocopy of printed version from Poetry 102, pages 292-298.
    - Typescript of "Pursuit", not before 1956 February (Box 12, Folder 206, Item 1)
      Carbon typescript of "Pursuit" annotated by Sylvia Plath. Annotated at top in SP's hand: "Sold: Atlantic Monthly $50 August 1956 / everything that flames upon the night man's own resinous heart has fed" [from W.B. Yeats' poem "Two Songs from a Play"].
    - Printed version of "Pursuit", 1957 January (Box 12, Folder 206, Item 2)
      Printed version from The Atlantic Monthly volume 199. Two copies, one annotated by Sylvia Plath.
    - Printed version of "Pursuit", 1957 January (Box 12, Folder 206, Item 3)
      Two copies of printed version from The Atlantic Monthly volume 199. "HUGHES" in Sylvia Plath's hand on front cover, as well as annotation by Aurelia Plath.
    - Typescript of "The Queen's Complaint", between 1957 September and 1958 September (Box 12, Folder 207, Item 1)
    - Printed version of "The Queen's Complaint", 1969 July 31 (Box 44, Folder 1, Item 2)
      Proof copy for the printed version for Times Literary Supplement 1969 Jul 31 with the published title "Complaint of the Crossed Queen" and date of composition, 1956. Published with four other "Early unpublished poems by Sylvia Plath": "Battle-Scene from the Comic Operatic Fantasy 'The Seafarer,'" "Dialogue en Route," "Letter to a Purist," and "Dream of the Hearse-Driver." Also includes a photograph of Sylvia Plath.
    - Holograph of "The Rabbit Catcher", undated; 4 pages (Box 12, Folder 208, Item 1)
      Holograph of "The Rabbit Catcher", variant title "Snares", numbered 1-4 by Sylvia Plath. The back of page 1 has Sylvia Plath's The Bell Jar early draft, chapter 3, page 1. The backs of pages 2-3 have Sylvia Plath's The Bell Jar early draft chapter 3, pages 14-15. The back of page 4 has The Bell Jar second draft, chapter 17, page 1.
    - Holograph and typescript of "The Rabbit Catcher", undated; 2 pages (Box 12, Folder 208, Item 2)
      Revised holograph and typescript of "The Rabbit Catcher", variant title "Snares", pages numbered 5-6 by Sylvia Plath. The backs of the pages have pages from Sylvia Plath's The Bell Jar second draft. The back of page 5 is chapter 17, page 2; the back of page 6 is chapter 6, page 15.
    - Typescript of "The Rabbit Catcher", 1962 May 21; 1 pages; Typed on pink Smith College memorandum paper. (Box 12, Folder 208, Item 3)
      Revised typescript of "The Rabbit Catcher" with Sylvia Plath's The Bell Jar second draft, chapter 16, page 16 on the back of the page.
    - Typescript of "The Rabbit Catcher", 1962 May 21; 1 pages (Box 12, Folder 208, Item 4)
      Carbon typescript of "The Rabbit Catcher" with Observer and BBC written and bracketed at the top by Sylvia Plath.
    - Galley proof of "The Rabbit Catcher" and "Event", undated; 1 pages (Box 12, Folder 208, Item 5)
      Corrected galley proof from Observer.
    - Typescript of "The Rabbit Catcher", undated; 1 pages (Box 12, Folder 208, Item 6)
    - Photocopy of printed version of "The Rabbit Catcher", 1965 February 7 (Box 12, Folder 208, Item 7)
      Photocopy of printed version from Observer Review 1965 Feb 7, page 26.
      Gift of Nick Gammage.
    - Typescript of "The Ravaged Face", 1 pages (Box 12, Folder 209)
      Typescript of "The Ravaged Face" page numbered 64, probably from the book "The Bull of Bendylaw" [1958-1959]
    - Typescript of "Recantation" (Box 12, Folder 210, Item 1)
      Carbon typescript of "Recantation" with variant title "The Dying Witch Addresses Her Young Apprentice." The page is numbered 31, probably from the book "The Bull of Bendylaw" [1958-1959]. "1957: Sold Accent" and "(Accent)" are written next to the title in Sylvia Plath's hand.
    - Typescript of "Recantation", 1 pages (Box 12, Folder 210, Item 2)
      Carbon typescript of "Recantation" page numbered 25, probably from the book "Two Lovers and a Beachcomber" [1956-1957].
    - Printed version of "Recantation" and "Tinker Jack and the Tidy Waves", autumn 1957 (Box 12, Folder 210, Item 3)
      Printed version from Accent volume 17, pages 247-248. Annotated by Sylvia Plath.
    - Printed version of "Recantation", autumn 1957 (Box 12, Folder 210, Item 4)
      Printed version from Accent volume 17, pages 247-248. Annotated by Aurelia Plath.
    - Typescript of "Reflections at Twelve", between 1957 September and 1958 September (Box 12, Folder 211)
      Not printed in Collected Poems
    - Typescript of "Resolve", circa 1958 February (Box 12, Folder 212, Item 1)
    - Photocopy of printed version of "Resolve", "Street Song", "Aerialist", and "Natural History", 1969 February 7 (Box 12, Folder 212, Item 2)
      Photocopy of printed version from Cambridge Review volume 90, number 2187, page 245.
    - Typescript of "Rhyme" (Box 12, Folder 213)
      Typescript of "Rhyme" page numbered 20, probably from the book "The Bull of Bendylaw" [1958-1959].
    - Typescript of "The Rival", between 1961 August and 1962 December; 2 pages (Box 12, Folder 214, Item 1)
      Typescript of "The Rival" with one autograph correction of a spelling error. The poem is divided into three numbered sections.
    - Typescript of "The Rival", between 1961 August and 1962 December; 2 pages (Box 12, Folder 214, Item 2)
      Carbon typescript of "The Rival" revised and annotated by Sylvia Plath. "July 1961 Observer" is annotated at the top in Sylvia Plath's hand.
    - Typescript of "The Rival", between 1961 August and 1962 December (Box 12, Folder 214, Item 3)
      Typescript of "The Rival" revised by Sylvia Plath.
    - Photocopy of typescript of part three of "The Rival", undated (Box 12, Folder 214, Item 4)
    - Photocopy of a typeset proof of "The Rival" and "Finisterre", undated (Box 12, Folder 214, Item 5)
      Photocopy of an annotated typeset proof of "The Rival" and "Finisterre."
      Original filed with "Finisterre."
    - Printed version of "The Rival", 1962 January 21 (Box 12, Folder 214, Item 6)
      Printed version from The Observer Weekend Review 1962 Jan 21, page 31.
    - Typescript of "Riverside Reverie", undated (Box 12, Folder 215, Item 1)
      Typescript of "Riverside Reverie" annotated by Sylvia Plath. "revision sold to C.S. Monitor $3.50 August 1952" is annotated at the top of the page in Sylvia Plath's hand. This poem is not printed in Collected Poems.
    - Photocopy of printed version of "Riverside Reverie", 1952 September 9 (Box 12, Folder 215, Item 2)
      Photocopy of printed version in The Christian Science Monitor.
    - Typescript of "Rondeau", probably 1955 (Box 12, Folder 216, Item 1)
      Typescript of "Rondeau" annotated by Alfred Young Fisher. This poem is not printed in Collected Poems.
    - Typescript of "Rondeau", between 1957 September and 1958 September (Box 12, Folder 216, Item 2)
      This poem is not printed in Collected Poems.
    - Typescript of "Rondeau Redoublé", probably 1955 (Box 12, Folder 217)
      Typescript of "Rondeau Redoublé" annotated by Alfred Young Fisher. This poem is not printed in Collected Poems.
    - Typescript of Sylvia Plath's translations of Pierre de. Ronsard's "Amours", circa 1956; 2 pages (Box 12, Folder 218)
      Revised typescript of translations of Pierre de. Ronsard's "Amours" XI, XII, XIV, and XVIII. "Tu m'as donné ta boue et j'en ai fait de l'or" is annotated in Sylvia Plath's hand from her copy of Les Fleurs du Mal by Charles Baudelaire (Oxford: Blackwell, 1953). Verso: bottom half on unidentified quotations (original and carbon), undated.
    - Typescript of "Sculptor", 1959 April 26 (Box 12, Folder 219, Item 1)
      Typescript of "Sculptor" dated by Aurelia Plath.
    - Printed version of "Sculptor", 1959 May (Box 12, Folder 219, Item 2)
      Three copies of printed version from The Grecourt Review (Smith College, Northampton, MA), volume 2, page 282. One copy is an offprint with printed cover, inscribed by Sylvia Plath: "To Mother – from Sylvia with love"; two copies are clippings annotated in Sylvia Plath's hand.
    - Typescript of "Second Winter", probably 1955 (Box 12, Folder 220, Item 1)
      Typescript of "Second Winter" annotated by Alfred Young Fisher.
    - Typescript of "Second Winter", probably 1952-1955 (Box 12, Folder 220, Item 2)
      Typescript of "Second Winter" annotated in Sylvia Plath's hand: "Accepted: The Lyric July 1955 (for December) Sold: Ladies Home Journal 1958". Not printed in Collected Poems.
    - Photocopy of printed version of "Second Winter" and "Prologue to Spring", 1956 April 10 (Box 12, Folder 220, Item 3)
      Photocopy of printed version from The Sophian Smith College, volume 4, number 41, page 2.
      Original: Box 12, Folder 203, item 2.
    - Photocopy of printed version of "Second Winter" and "To a Jilted Lover", winter 1956 (Box 12, Folder 220, Item 4)
      Photocopy of printed version from The Lyric volume 36, number 1, page 11. "To a Jilted Lover" is published as "Apotheosis."
      Original filed with: "To A Jilted Lover" (Box 14, Folder 272).
    - Printed version of "Second Winter", 1958 December (Box 12, Folder 220, Item 5)
      Printed version from Ladies' Home Journal volume 75, number 12, page 143, annotated by Sylvia Plath.
    - Printed version of "Second Winter", 1958 December (Box 43, Folder 1, Item 6)
      Printed version in Ladies' Home Journal volume 75, number 12, page 143, annotated by Aurelia Plath.
    - Holograph of "A Secret", 1962 October 10; 2 pages; Written on pink Smith College memorandum paper. (Box 12, Folder 221, Item 1)
      Holograph of "A Secret" with pages from an undated holograph of Ted Hughes' play "The Calm" on the reverse. Pages of "The Calm" are numbered 16 and 17 by Ted Hughes.
    - Typescript of "A Secret", 1962 October 10; 2 pages; Typed on pink Smith College memorandum paper. (Box 12, Folder 221, Item 2)
      Revised typescript of "A Secret" with pages from an undated holograph of Ted Hughes' play "The Calm" on the reverse. Pages of "The Calm" are numbered 11 and 15 by Ted Hughes.
    - Typescript of "A Secret", 1962 October 10; 2 pages; Typed on pink Smith College memorandum paper. (Box 12, Folder 221, Item 3)
      Corrected typescript of "A Secret" with number of lines calculated at the top in Sylvia Plath's hand. The reverse has pages from an undated holograph of Ted Hughes' play "The Calm" numbered 9 and 10 by Ted Hughes.
    - Typescript of "A Secret", 1962 October 10; 3 pages (Box 12, Folder 221, Item 4)
      Revised typescripts (original and carbons) of "A Secret." The last two lines are retyped at the bottom of carbon 1 and the last 3 lines are retyped at the bottom of carbon 2.
    - Corrected typescript of "A Secret", undated; 1 pages (Box 12, Folder 221, Item 5)
    - Photocopy of a holograph of "Sheep in Fog", undated; 1 pages (Box 12, Folder 222, Item 1)
      Photocopy of a holograph of "Sheep in Fog", variant title "For Sheep", page numbered 1 by Sylvia Plath. The back of the page has Sylvia Plath's Three Women page 3.
      Original drafts owned by Frieda Hughes in 1981.
    - Photocopy of a holograph of "Sheep in Fog", undated; 1 pages (Box 12, Folder 222, Item 2)
      Photocopy of a holograph of "Sheep in Fog", variant title "For Sheep", numbered 2 by Sylvia Plath. The back of the page has Sylvia Plath's Three Women page 2.
    - Photocopy of a holograph of "Sheep in Fog", 1962 December 2; 1 pages (Box 12, Folder 222, Item 3)
      Photocopy of a holograph of "Sheep in Fog", variant title "For Sheep", numbered 3 by Sylvia Plath. The back of the page: Sylvia Plath. Page 11 of an unidentified story.
    - Photocopy of a typescript of "Sheep in Fog", 1962 December 2; 1 pages (Box 12, Folder 222, Item 4)
      Photocopy of a revised typescript of "Sheep in Fog", variant title "For Sheep". The back of the page: Sylvia Plath. Page 10 of an unidentified story.
    - Typescript of "Sheep in Fog", undated; 1 pages (Box 12, Folder 222, Item 5)
      Typescript carbon of "Sheep in Fog", variant title "Fog Sheep", double-spaced.
    - Photocopy and original typescript of "Sheep in Fog", 1962 December 2-1963 January 28; 3 pages (Box 12, Folder 222, Item 6)
      Corrected typescript (original and carbons) of "Sheep in Fog". On carbon 2 the title is changed to "Sheep in Fog" and the last stanza is rewritten and dated Jan. 28 1963. Two pages are photocopies.
    - Photocopy of a typescript of "Sheep in Fog", 1962 December 2-1963 January 28 (Box 12, Folder 222, Item 7)
      Typescript carbon of "Sheep in Fog" corrected and annotated by Sylvia Plath and revised Jan 28, 1963.
    - Typescript of "Sleep in the Mojave Desert", 1960 July 5 (Box 12, Folder 223, Item 1)
      Typescript of "Sleep in the Mojave Desert" annotated by Sylvia Plath. "Harper's, Observer, BBC" is annotated at the top in Sylvia Plath's hand.
    - Typescript of "Sleep in the Mojave Desert", between 1961 August and 1962 December (Box 12, Folder 223, Item 2)
      Typescript of "Sleep in the Mojave Desert" with "(Harper's)/(Observer)/(BBC)" typed at the top.
    - Typescript of "Sleep in the Mojave Desert", probably 1961 (Box 12, Folder 223, Item 3)
      Original and carbon typescript of "Sleep in the Mojave Desert."
    - Galley proof of "Sleep in the Mojave Desert", undated (Box 12, Folder 223, Item 4)
      Galley proof for publication in The Observer.
    - Printed version of "Sleep in the Mojave Desert", 1961 November 19 (Box 12, Folder 223, Item 5)
      Printed version from The Observer page 28, with published title "Mojave Desert." Annotated by Sylvia Plath.
    - Printed version of "Sleep in the Mojave Desert", 1962 February (Box 12, Folder 223, Item 6)
      Printed version from Harper's volume 224, page 36. Annotated by Sylvia Plath.
    - Printed version of "Sleep in the Mojave Desert", 1962 February (Box 12, Folder 223, Item 7)
      Printed version from Harper's volume 224, page 36. Annotated by Aurelia Plath.
    - Typescript of "The Sleepers", circa 1959 (Box 12, Folder 224, Item 1)
      Original and carbon typescript of "The Sleepers." The carbon is annotated in Sylvia Plath's hand "London Magazine", the title is underlined in red pencil, and the page is numbered 24.
    - Galley proof of "The Sleepers" and "Full Fathom Five", probably 1960 (Box 12, Folder 224, Item 2)
      Galley proof from The London Magazine.
    - Printed version of "The Sleepers" and "Full Fathom Five", 1960 June (Box 12, Folder 224, Item 3)
      Printed version in The London Magazine volume 7, number 6, page 11. Poems are headed "Sylvia Plath Two Poems", with extra pages annotated by Sylvia Plath.
    - Printed version of "Snakecharmer", "Lorelei", and "The Disquieting Muses", 1959 March (Box 13, Folder 225, Item 1)
      Printed version from The London Magazine volume 6, pages 33-36, annotated by Sylvia Plath.
    - Photocopy of a typescript of "Snakecharmer" (Box 13, Folder 225, Item 2)
      Photocopy of a typescript of "Snakecharmer" numbered 47 and 48, probably from the book The Colossus [1959-1960].
    - Typescript of "The Snowman on the Moor", between 1956 December and 1957 June (Box 13, Folder 226, Item 1)
      Carbon typescript of "The Snowman on the Moor" annotated by Sylvia Plath. "Sold: Poetry 1957" is annotated at the top in Sylvia Plath's hand.
    - Typescript of "The Snowman on the Moor", 2 pages (Box 13, Folder 226, Item 2)
      Carbon typescript of "The Snowman on the Moor" pages numbered 18 and 19, probably from the book "Two Lovers and a Beachcomber" [1956-1957].
    - Printed version of "The Snowman on the Moor", "Sow", "Ella Mason and Her Eleven Cats", and "On the Difficulty of Conjuring Up a Dryad", 1957 July (Box 13, Folder 226, Item 3)
      Printed version from Poetry volume 90, pages 229-36. "Poetry (Chicago), July 1957" is typed at the top, possibly by Sylvia Plath.
    - Printed version of "The Snowman on the Moor", 1957 July (Box 13, Folder 226, Item 4)
      Printed version from Poetry volume 90, pages 229-31, annotated by Aurelia Plath.
    - Typescript of "Soliloquy of the Solipsist", 2 pages (Box 13, Folder 227)
      Typescript carbon of "Soliloquy of the Solipsist" pages numbered 37 and 38, probably from the book "Two Lovers and a Beachcomber" [1956-1957].
    - Photocopy of printed version of "Something there was about the time", "A time of clear white understanding", and "The sweet sickish female odor", undated (Box 13, Folder 228)
      Photocopy of printed version in Trois poemes inedits de Sylvia Plath. Paris: Editions Dufour, [n.d.]. Copy number 3 of an edition of 103 copies, 3 of which included an original holograph of one of the poems. Titles from first lines.
      Purchased from James Cummins (McConnell-Bohning Fund), 7/10/1996.
      Original filed with Writings. Poems. "A time of clear white understanding:".
    - Typescript of "Song for a Revolutionary Love", probably 1955 (Box 13, Folder 229)
      Typescript of "Song for a Revolutionary Love" annotated by Alfred Young Fisher.
    - Printed version of "Song for a Summer's Day", 1959 August 18 (Box 13, Folder 230)
      Printed version from The Christian Science Monitor 1959 Aug 18, page 18. Annotated by Sylvia Plath. With a photocopy of the full page from CSM and a transcription of a version of the poem from the Lilly Library.
    - Typescript of "Song for a Thaw", probably 1955 (Box 13, Folder 231)
      Typescript of "Song for a Thaw" annotated by Alfred Young Fisher. Not printed in Collected Poems.
    - Typescript of "Song of Eve", probably 1955 (Box 13, Folder 232, Item 1)
      Typescript of "Song of Eve" annotated by Alfred Young Fisher. Not printed in Collected Poems.
    - Typescript of "Song of Eve", between 1957 September and 1958 September (Box 13, Folder 232, Item 2)
      Typescript of "Song of Eve", not printed in Collected Poems.
    - Typescript of "Sonnet for a Green-Eyed Sailor", approximately 1955 April (Box 13, Folder 233)
      Not printed in Collected Poems.
    - Typescript of "Sonnet: The Suitcases are Packed Again", undated (Box 13, Folder 234)
      Typescript of "Sonnet: The Suitcases are Packed Again" with variant title "The Suitcases are Packed Again (Sonnet)", annotated by Alfred Young Fisher and Sylvia Plath. "Sold to Seventeen June 1952 $5" is annotated in Sylvia Plath's hand. Not printed in Collected Poems.
    - Printed version of "Sonnet: The Suitcases are Packed Again", 1953 March (Box 43.1, Folder 12)
      Printed version in Seventeen page 19, published as "The Suitcases are Packed Again." "From the library of Sylvia Plath" is annotated on the front cover by her and Aurelia Plath.
    - Typescript of "Sonnet: To a Shade", 1955 March 10 (Box 13, Folder 235)
      Typescript of "Sonnet: To a Shade", with variant title "Sonnet to a Shade", annotated by Alfred Young Fisher. "For Mr. Fisher, march 10, 1955" is typed on the reverse. Not printed in Collected Poems.
    - Typescript of "Sonnet to Satan", probably 1955 (Box 13, Folder 236)
      Typescript of "Sonnet to Sata" annotated by Alfred Young Fisher.
    - Typescript of "Sonnet: To Time", 1950 (Box 13, Folder 237)
      Typescript of "Sonnet: To Time" dated 1950 by Aurelia Plath. The typed initials "S.P." are at the end and "x" at the left of the last 2 lines.
    - Typescript of "A Sorcerer Bids Farewell to Seem", probably 1955 (Box 13, Folder 238)
      Typescript of "A Sorcerer Bids Farewell to Seem" annotated by Alfred Young Fisher.
    - Printed version of "Southern Sunrise", 1959 August 26 (Box 13, Folder 239)
      Printed version from The Christian Science Monitor 1959 Aug 26, page 8, annotated by Sylvia Plath. The date (August 27, 1959) is written in Sylvia Plath's hand. With a photocopy of the full page from the CSM.
    - Typescript of "Sow", 2 pages (Box 13, Folder 240, Item 1)
      Carbon typescript of "Sow" with pages numbered 32 and 33, probably from the book "Two Lovers and a Beachcomber" [1956-1957].
    - Photocopy of printed version of "Sow", 1957 July (Box 13, Folder 240, Item 2)
      Photocopy of printed version from Poetry volume 90, pages 231-33.
    - Typescript of "Spider", between 1957 September and 1958 September (Box 13, Folder 241)
    - Typescript of "Spinster", 1 pages (Box 13, Folder 242, Item 1)
      Carbon typescript of "Spinster" with page numbered 9, probably from the book "Two Lovers and a Beachcomber" [1956-1957].
    - Printed version of "Spinster", winter 1958 (Box 13, Folder 242, Item 2)
      Two copies of printed version from Smith Alumnae Quarterly volume 49, page 71. One copy is annotated by Sylvia Plath.
    - Typeset proof of "Spinster", Traces of tape at top and bottom, indicating it may have been removed from SP's scrapbook. (Box 13, Folder 242, Item 3)
      Typeset proof of "Spinster", source unknown.
    - Printed version of "Spinster" and "Black Rook in Rainy Weather", 1958 June (Box 13, Folder 242, Item 4)
      Printed version from London Magazine 1958 June, pages 46-48, annotated by Sylvia Plath.
    - Photocopy of a typescript of "Spinster" (Box 13, Folder 242, Item 5)
      Photocopy of a typescript of "Spinster" with pages numbered 60-61, probably from the book The Colossus [1959-1960].
    - Printed version of "Spinster" and "Vanity Fair", spring 1957 (Box 13, Folder 242, Item 6)
      Printed version in Gemini volume 1, number 1, page 6. The cover is annotated by Aurelia Plath.
    - Typescript of "Stars Over the Dordogne", between 1961 August and 1962 December (Box 13, Folder 243)
      Typescript carbon of "Stars Over the Dordogne" annotated by Sylvia Plath. "Poetry Chicago" is annotated at the top in Sylvia Plath's hand.
    - Typescript of "Stillborn", between 1960 January and 1961 August; Original and carbon typescript. (Box 13, Folder 244, Item 1)
    - Photocopy of printed version of "Stillborn", "Surgeon at 2 a.m." and "Black Rook in Rainy Weather", 1971 September (Box 13, Folder 244, Item 2)
      Photocopy of printed version from Mademoiselle volume 73, number 5, pages 160-161. Page is headed "Sylvia Plath Three Poems and a Remembrance." The printed version includes the three poems and a biographical note on Sylvia Plath by Ellen A. Stoianoff. Clipping includes cover and contents page from issue. Annotated by Aurelia Plath.
    - Holograph of "Stings", undated (Box 13, Folder 245, Item 1)
      Holograph of "Stings" page numbered 2. The back of the page has Ted Hughes' "Lines to a Newborn Baby": typescript (carbon), 1960 May.
    - Typescript of "Stings", undated; 1 pages (Box 13, Folder 245, Item 2)